Lorenzo Feruglio

PhD Candidate at Politecnico di Torino

Via Baretti 26, C/O Lo Giudice
10129 Torino
Italy

\$\partial +39 3290918239\$

\times lorenzo.feruglio@gmail.com

\$\tilde{\mathbb{n}} \text{ lorenzoferuglio.github.io}

in lorenzoferuglio

Education

2006–2009 **Aerospace Engineering**, *Politecnico di Torino*, Torino, *Bachelor's Degree*.

2009–2012 **Aerospace Engineering**, *Politecnico di Torino*, Torino, *Master of Science*. Graduated with Honors

2014–now **Aerospace Engineering**, *Politecnico di Torino*, Torino, *PhD Candidate*.

2014 Exchange student at **Massachussetts Institute of Technology** for the project 'CubeSat for Space Exploration: a new paradigm for Planetary Science Missions'

2015 Visiting Student Researcher (JVSRP) at Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL) for Mission Autonomy Research

Summary

research Autonomous Space Systems, Artificial Intelligence

experience Five years and counting of hands-on experience with CubeSats

Polito CubeSat Team Leader for C&DH, AOCS and GCS design

knowledge Detailed subsystem knowledge (AOCS, C&DH)

STK, Matlab, Python, C

hands-on e-st@r CubeSat project followed from design to LEOP

projects e-st@rll CubeSat currently performing Environmental Test Campaign at ESTEC

among Fly Your Satellite! Competition 3-STAR CubeSat for GNSS Remote Sensing

Experience

PhD Student - Space Engineering

2014-now Mission Autonomy Engineer, Politecnico di Torino, Torino.

Methodologies and Technologies to Improve Small Satellites Space Mission Autonomy Current field of research:

- o Neural networks for image quality assessment and event detection
- Fuzzy logics for failure detection of actuators
- Definition of case studies (Interplanetary CubeSats) in order to investigate on mission autonomy-enhancing technologies
- Genetic Algorithms to optimize Multi-Attribute Tradespace Exploration problems
- Hardware-In-The-Loop testing of training algorithms for neural networks for asteroid recognition

Space System Engineer

2013-2014 Assistant Researcher, Politecnico di Torino, Torino.

Capture and De-Orbiting Technologies.

Field of Research:

- Development of a Simulator Technology to perform mission analyses and In-The-Loop simulations
- Research on GNC strategies for the latest phases of a rendez-vous and mating manoeuvre
- Attitude Determination and Control Algorithms testing on specific hardware (ARM architecture)
- Code development and upgrading for ADCS and OBC subsystems (e-st@rII CubeSat)
- o e-st@r-II CubeSat Subsystem and System Functional Testing

2012–2013 **Operation Architecture Engineer**, SES (contractor), Luxembourg.

Efficient Automation of Satellite Operations (EASO Project).

Detailed achievements:

- Development, verification and validation of automated procedures for Satellite Operations
- Payload and Bus operation procedures for the SES Orbital fleet:
 - Dynamic Satellite Simulators (Orbital)
 - AOCS, TCR, TCS, EPS, CDH procedures development and subsystem analysis by means of DSS
 - Ground Control Station Software (SCORPIO)
- o SPELL, Python, Eclipse

2009–2012 Polito CubeSat Team - Team member, Politecnico di Torino, Italy.

Member of the University CubeSat Team, developing and launching 1U+ CubeSats. Detailed achievements:

- Satellite (1U and 3U CubeSat) experience:
 - System Engineering methodologies
 - ADCS, C&DH Subsystem development and testing
 - CubeSat functional testing (test definition and execution)
 - ECSS standards for software development and testing
 - Real-time OS (Salvo, RTLinux)

Computer skills

Analysis STK, Dynamic Satellite Simulation (AOCS, Failure Detection Systems), Space Debris Mitigation

Programming C, C++, Python, Matlab/Simulink

System Eng Multi-Attribute Tradespace Exploration, Satellite System Budgets, SysML, UML, Requirements and Functional Analysis

Embedded MPS430, ARM9, Satellite Hardware-In-The-Loop Testing

Miscellaneous MS Office, Visio, LaTex

OS UNIX (Ubuntu), RTLinux, Windows

Languages

Italian Mother language

English Proficient

French Basic Knowledge German Basic Knowledge